# LOIS VALDEZ

Enthusiastic school librarian with a talent for planning and delivering educational activities to promote an appreciation of literature. Skilled at providing training and orientation for library staff and creatingan inviting, purposeful learning atmosphere. Specialized knowledge of managing IT suites and digital resource systems.

456 Main Road, Houston, TX 21098 I.valdegmyema il.com (123) 456-7690

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### SCHOOL LIBRARIAN

Cypress-Fairbanks Independent School District, Houston, TX September 2019 - Present

# SALES ASSOCIATE

UHD Bookstore, Houston, TX September 2017 - August 2019

- Work in collaboration with library departments at partner schools to ensure a comprehensive resource collection and arrange inter-school material loans
- Manage library budget and select high-quality, appropriate, and varied print and digital resources
- Maintain organized cataloging and circulation systems and keep accurate inventory records
- Supervise students' library use and provide assistance and reading advice as necessary
- Promote reading culture and a love of literature through extra-curricular activities, including book groups, incentive schemes, and study skills sessions
- Cultivated a comprehensive knowledge of classic and modern literature and used expertise to recommend suitable texts
- Maintained a tidy and attractive store environment and well-organized shelving system
- Responded to customer queries promptly in person and via phone and email

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts in Literature University Of Houston, Houston, Tx Septem be r 2013 - Ju ne 2017

Master of Science in School Library and Information Science University Of Houston Clear Lake, Houston, Tx September 2017 - June 2019

# **KEY SKILLS**

- Information technology and data basing
- ♦ Budget management
- ♦ Resource selection
- Teaching research and comprehension skills
- Staff training and performance management
- Collaborating with partner schools and outside organizations

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

 Sc h ool Li b raria n Sta n da rd Certificate, 2019